<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Toolforge</title>
    <author email="asmedes@home.nl">Arjen Smedes</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

  <section name="Getting Started">

  <p>
    This page describes how to get the CLI tool started on your local
    machine.
  </p>

  </section>

  <section name="Compiling dependent modules">

  <p>
    The CLI module depends on three other toolforge modules : <code>toolforge-core</code>,
    <code>karma-core</code> and <code>karma-launcher</code>. These modules
    have to be compiled and deployed to your local Maven repository. The
    easiest route is to execute the following steps:
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li/>Check out the full <code>toolforge</code> project from Sourceforge.
    <li/>On <code>toolforge-core</code> execute the <code>jar:install</code> goal. This will
    install <code>toolforge-core-1.0-dev.jar</code> into the local Maven
    repository (well, that is assuming you have that as your default
    repository.
    <li/>On <code>karma-launcher</code> execute the <code>jar</code> goal. This will
    compile and package <code>karma-launcher-1.2.jar</code> into the
    <code>target</code> directory of the <code>karma-launcher</code>
    module.
    <li/>Refer to the documentation site for the <code>karma-core</code> and
    follow the steps for the JUnit test setup. There is a manual procedure to
    follow before the <code>karma-core</code> module can be succesfully
    deployed as a jar in the Maven repository. The quick route is to disable
    junit tests in the <code>karma-core</code> module and execute the
    <code>jar:install</code> goal upon the module.
    <li/>Last, but not least, the <code>karma-cli</code> module should be
    compiled. Use <code>java:compile</code> on the <code>karma-cli</code>
    module to compile the sources into the <code>target/classes</code>
    directory.
  </ul>

  </section>

  <section name="Configuration">

  <p>
    Karma (whichever user interface you use) depends on a few configuration
    items that must be present. Follow the following steps to configure your
    local environment.
  </p>

  <ul>
    <li/>Create a configuration directory in your user home directory. The
    location is really optional, but it is recommended to create the directory
    in your home directory. A good one is <code>$HOME/.karma</code>
    <li/>Create a <code>karma.properties</code>-file in that directory and
    configure the following properties:
    <table>
      <tr>
        <th>Name</th>
	<th>Value</th>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td><code>locale</code></td>
	<td><code>en</code> (or <code>nl</code>)</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td><code>karma.location-store.directory</code></td>
	<td><code>/tmp/toolforge/locations</code>)</td>
      </tr>
    </table>
    <li/>Copy
    <code>karma-core/resources/templates/locations.xml.template</code> as
    <code>locations.xml</code> (only the extension is important) to the
    directory you configured for <code>karma.location-store.directory</code>
    in <code>karma.properties</code>. 
    <li/>Copy <code>karma-launcher-1.2.jar</code> into the <code>lib</code>
    directory of your <code>karma-cli</code> module directory (create that
    directory if it doesn't exist.
  </ul>

  </section>

  <section name="Start the Command Line Interface">

  <p>
    All set ? Start the command line interface. Use <code>bin/karma</code> on
    a Unix system to see the thing happening (Windows users wait a bit or do
    it yourself for now).
  </p>

  </section>

</body>

</document>
