<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Toolforge User Documentation</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

  <section name="Administration guide">

  <p>
    Karma works with manifests and modules. Manifests consist of a certain amount of modules.
    A manifests is defined in an XML file, which defines the properties of the manifest and the
    modules the manifest contains. Modules are stored in a
    version control system, and identified by a <code>location</code>
    attribute in the manifest file (see below). This attribute is used by
    Karma to locate the correct version control system (its location).
  </p>

  <p>
    The manifest and location configuration are is in a
    version control repository as well. The so-called `manifest-store` and
    `location-store`. Both of these will have to be present for Karma to
    actually do something usefull.
  </p>

  <p>
    In the case of CVS you have to create a <strong>manifests</strong> and
    <strong>locations</strong> module in your repository. It is also possible
    to create one module (say <strong>karma</strong>) and create a manifests
    and locations module under that.
    <br/>
    Next to the manifests and locations module you have to define a
    <strong>modules</strong> module. In this module the actual modules are stored.
    I.e. :
  </p>

    <source>
CVSROOT/
   manifests
   locations
   modules
    </source>

    <p>
      or:
    </p>

    <source>
CVSROOT/
   karma/
      manifests
      locations
      modules
    </source>

  <subsection name="The manifest store">

  <p>
    Software modules are grouped in a so-called manifests. These manifests are
    xml files, following the
    `http://www.toolforge.org/specifications/karma/manifest.dtd`
    definition. Karma is capable of checking out these manifest files from a
    (CVS) repository. The local checkout of this module (which must be named :
    manifests) is called the 'manifest-store'. During startup of Karma, the
    manifest-store configuration will be checked and asked for if missing (see
    <a href="getting-started.html">getting started</a>).
    A local CVS repository works as well.
  </p>

  <p>
    See the <a href="reference/working-context/index.html">Reference
    Documentation </a> for more information on the configuration aspects of the
    manifest store.
  </p>

  <p>
   Create a file <code>helloworld.xml</code> and add it to your manifest store
   (check it in into your manifest store module in a CVS repository:
  </p>

  <source>
  <![CDATA[
<?xml version="1.0"?>

<manifest type="development" version="1-0">
  <modules>
    <module name="helloworld" location="local"/>
  </modules>
</manifest>
  ]]>
  </source>
  
  </subsection>

  <subsection name="The location store">

  <p>
     Each module has a location. Right now, all modules have a location
     identifying a CVS repository. Locations are configured in xml files,
     following the http://www.toolforge.org/specifications/karma/location.dtd
     definition. Karma is capable of checking out these location files from a
     (CVS) repository. The local checkout of this module (which must be named
     : locations) is called the 'location-store'. During startup of Karma, the
     location-store configuration will be checked and asked for if
     missing. You have to provide these properties to Karma which will be
     written in
     <code>$USER_HOME/.karma/&lt;working-context&gt;/workingcontext.properties</code>. A
     local CVS repository works as well.
  </p>

  <p>
    See the <a href="/reference/working-context/index.html">reference</a>
    documentation for more information on the configuration aspects of the
    location store.
  </p>

  <p>
    The following could be your starter location. Create a file
    <code>locations.xml</code> and add it to your location store in the CVS
    repository:
  </p>

  <source>

  <![CDATA[
<?xml version="1.0"?>

<loc:locations>

  <loc:location type="cvs-repository" id="local">
    <loc:protocol>local</loc:protocol>
    <loc:host>localhost</loc:host>
    <loc:port>2401</loc:port>
    <loc:repository>/home/cvs</loc:repository>
    <loc:module-offset></loc:module-offset>
  </loc:location>

</loc:locations>
  ]]>
  </source>

  <p>
    The mapping between the manifest and the location is made via
    <code>id="local"</code>.
  </p>

  </subsection>

  <subsection name="Authentication configuration">

  <p>
    Version control repositories, such as CVS, can be behind an authentication
    layer. If so, you will need a username and password. Karma maps each
    location to authentication data. This authentication data is (Karma R1.0)
    required to be in a file called <code>$USER_HOME/.cvspass</code>. If you
    have ever used CVS command-line tools, you might have it on your system
    already. For each location (a CVS location will create a CVSROOT from it),
    a line should be created in the <code>.cvspass</code> file. This includes
    the location configuration for the manifest-store and the
    location-store. A general <code>.cvspass</code> file looks like:
  </p>

  <source>
/1 :pserver:asmedes@cvs.toolforge.nl:2401/cvs/karma B$#H er_9
/1 :pserver:asmedes@cvs.toolforge.nl:2418/cvs/cli B$^G er_9
  </source>

  <p>
    The scrambled password is stored in this file as well. Ask your
    administrator (or send us an email <a
    href="mailto:support@toolforge.org">support@toolforge.org</a> for more
    info if you haven't got a clue...).
  </p>

  <p> 
    The authentication data that Karma requires has to be available in
    <code>$USER_HOME/.karma</code>, in a file called
    <code>authenticators.xml</code>. The following snippet shows the
    <code>authenticators.xml</code> that maps to the location you configured
    above :
  </p>

  <source>
  <![CDATA[
<?xml version="1.0"?>

<authenticators>
  <authenticator working-context="default" id="local" username="asmedes"/>
</authenticators>
  ]]>
  </source>
  
  <p>
    Note that <code>asmedes</code> is the username in the CVS repository,
    although it is not required for a CVS repository that is local (the
    <code>:local:</code> protocol), Karma still needs it to keep track of who
    did what (history).
  </p>

  </subsection>

  </section>

  </body>

</document>
