<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Toolforge User Documentation</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

  <section name="Administration Stuff">

  <p>
    ...
  </p>

  <subsection name="The manifest store">

  <p>
    Software modules are grouped in a so-called manifests. These manifests are
    xml files, following the
    http://www.toolforge.org/specifications/karma/manifest.dtd
    definition. Karma is capable of checking out these manifest files from a
    (CVS) repository. The local checkout of this module (which must be named :
    manifests) is called the 'manifest-store'. During startup of Karma, the
    manifest-store configuration will be checked and asked for if missing. You
    have to provide these properties to Karma which will be written in
    <code>$USER_HOME/.karma/&lt;working-context&gt;/workingcontext.properties.</code>
    A local CVS repository works as well.
  </p>

  <p>
   Create a file <code>helloworld.xml</code> and add it to your
   <code>manifest</code> module in the CVS repository :
  </p>

  <source>
  <![CDATA[
  <?xml version="1.0"?>

  <manifest name="helloworld" type="development" version="1-0">
    <modules>
      <module name="helloworld" location="local"/>
    </modules>
  </manifest>
  ]]>
  </source>
  
  </subsection>

  <subsection name="The location store">

  <p>
     Each module has a location. Right now, all modules have a location
     identifying a CVS repository. Locations are configured in xml files,
     following the http://www.toolforge.org/specifications/karma/location.dtd
     definition. Karma is capable of checking out these location files from a
     (CVS) repository. The local checkout of this module (which must be named
     : locations) is called the 'location-store'. During startup of Karma, the
     location-store configuration will be checked and asked for if
     missing. You have to provide these properties to Karma which will be
     written in
     <code>$USER_HOME/.karma/&lt;working-context&gt;/workingcontext.properties</code>. A
     local CVS repository works as well.
  </p>

  <p>
    The following could be your starter location. Create a file
    <code>locations.xml</code> and add it to your <code>locations</code>
    module in the CVS repository :
  </p>

  <source>

  <![CDATA[
  <?xml version="1.0"?>

  <locations>

    <location type="cvs-repository" id="local">
      <protocol>local</protocol>
      <host>localhost</host>
      <port>2401</port>
      <repository>/home/cvs</repository>
    </location>

  </locations>
  ]]>
  </source>

  <p>
    The mapping between the manifest and the location is made via
    <code>id="local"</code>.
  </p>

  </subsection>

  <subsection name="Authentication configuration">

  <p>
    Version control repositories, such as CVS, can be behind an authentication
    layer. If so, you will need a username and password. Karma maps each
    location to authentication data. This authentication data is (Karma R1.0)
    required to be in a file called <code>$USER_HOME/.cvspass</code>. If you
    have ever used CVS command-line tools, you might have it on your system
    already. For each location (a CVS location will create a CVSROOT from it),
    a line should be created in the <code>.cvspass</code> file. This includes
    the location configuration for the manifest-store and the
    location-store. A general <code>.cvspass</code> file looks like:
  </p>

  <source>
    /1 :pserver:asmedes@cvs.toolforge.nl:2401/cvs/karma B$#H er_9
    /1 :pserver:asmedes@cvs.toolforge.nl:2418/cvs/cli B$^G er_9
  </source>

  <p>
    The scrambled password is stored in this file as well. Ask your
    administrator (or send us an email <a
    href="mailto:support@toolforge.org">support@toolforge.org</a> for more
    info if you haven't got a clue...).
  </p>

  <p> 
    The authentication data that Karma requires has to be available in
    <code>$USER_HOME/.karma</code>, in a file called
    <code>authenticators.xml</code>. The following snippet shows the
    <code>authenticators.xml</code> that maps to the location you configured
    above :
  </p>

  <source>
  <![CDATA[
  <?xml version="1.0"?>

  <authenticators>
    <authenticator id="local" username="asmedes"/>
  </authenticators>
  ]]>
  </source>
  
  <p>
    Note that <code>asmedes</code> is the username in the CVS repository,
    although it is not required for a CVS repository that is local (the
    <code>:local:</code> protocol), Karma still needs it to be maintain
    history.
  </p>

  </subsection>

  </section>

  </body>

</document>
