<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Toolforge Documentation</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

  <section name="What is Toolforge ?">

  <p>
    <b>Toolforge</b> is the Sourceforge project name for a suite of tools
    related to build, release and configuration management. The product is
    known as <b>Karma</b> which is derived from <b>C</b>ode <b>A</b>nd
    <b>R</b>elease <b>M</b>anagement <b>A</b>pplication, but 'CARMA' wasn't
    good enough a name for us.
  </p>

  </section>

  <section name="What is Karma ?">

  <p>
    Karma is a tool that is positioned in the following areas of software
    development:

    <ul>
      <li/>Component Management
      <li/>Version Management
      <li/>Build Management
      <li/>Release Management
    </ul>
  </p>

  <p>
    The tool (and more than that, its methodology) supports software
    developers and release managers in their quest to manage software systems,
    components and modules. A true enabler of a smooth software logistics
    process (yep ...).
  </p>

  <p>
    Component based development requires more than a version control system to
    manage source code and build tools to build that source code. It requires
    that software components can be easily managed, exchanged, reused.
  </p>

  <p>
    Our early releases of Karma showed that developers, familiar with tools
    like <a href="http://ant.apache.org">Ant</a> and <a
    href="http://maven.apache.org">Maven</a> needed to be convinced of the
    power of the Karma concept: <i>"We have Maven to do that.", "Why don't we
    build an extension to Ant for this ?"</i>. So far, we've been able to convince
    everyone that Karma offers more.
  </p>

  <p>
    Anyway, so far for the sales talk. All of it is true, but let's continue
    and make it happen.
  </p>

  </section>

  <section name="What is there to use ?">

<!--    <subsection name="Open source and free"> -->

    <p>
      The <b>Toolforge</b> project on <a
      href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/toolforge">Sourceforge</a>
      contains what is there to get. <b>Read</b> the <a href="basics.html">basics</a>
      section before anything else to get an idea of what Karma could mean for
      your organization.
    </p>

    <p>
      Released versions of Karma can be found at
      <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/toolforge">Sourceforge</a>.
    </p>

<!--    </subsection> -->

  </section>

  </body>

</document>
