<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Reference Documentation</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Locations">
      <p>
        Modules are stored in locations. Currently the only supported type of location
        is a CVS repository. We intend to add more types of locations after the 1.0
        release. Possible other types are subversion, disk, ClearCase.
      </p>
      <p>
        When creating a module you have to specify the location in which to create the module.
        When including a module in your manifest you have to specify the location of
        the module. For Karma this is the only way to know where to retrieve the modules.
      </p>
      <p>
        Locations are defined in an xml file. An example of such an xml file is:
<source>
<![CDATA[
  <?xml version="1.0" ?>

  <locations>
    <location type="cvs-repository" id="cvs-local">
      <protocol>[ local | ext | pserver ]</protocol>
      <host>localhost</host>
      <port>2401</port>
      <repository>/home/cvs</repository>
    </location>
  </locations>
]]>
</source>
        The <code>type</code> attribute specifies the type of the location, which currently
        has to be <code>cvs-repository</code>. The <code>id</code> attribute defined the unique
        id by which the location is identified. This <code>id</code> is used when specifying a module's
        location when creating it or including it in a manifest.
      </p>
      <p>
        In case of a <code>cvs-repository</code> type location the following elements are
        valid:
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>Element name</th>
            <th>Description</th>
            <th>Values</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>protocol</td>
            <td>Specifies which protocol is used for accessing the CVS server.</td>
            <td>local, pserver or ext</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>host</td>
            <td>
              The name of the server which hosts the CVS server. Is localhost in case
              of a local reporistory.
            </td>
            <td>E.g.: cvs.sf.net or localhost</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>port</td>
            <td>The port number. Ignored in case of a local repository.</td>
            <td>E.g. 2401.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>repository</td>
            <td>The full path to the location of the modules in the CVS repo.</td>
            <td>E.g. /cvs/karma/modules</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </p>

    </section>
 </body>
</document>