<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>
 <properties>
  <title>Karma Core</title>
 </properties>

<body>

<section name="Outstanding work for version 1.0">

<ul>

  <li/><s><code>view-manifest</code>; shows the status of a manifest. All modules
  will be checked against their status in the VCS. Discrepancies between local
  and remote versions are reported. It is a 'simple' overview.</s> What is left is the
  distinction between a development and a release manifest.

  <li/><code>build-all</code>; builds all modules (the manifest itself).

  <li/><code>test-all</code>; runs the unit tests of all modules.

  <li/><code>promote-module</code>; <s> adds a tag to the module in the VCS on a
  branch-level. The latest version of a module within a branch is determined
  and the version is incremented by 1. No fancy schemes are supported.
  At least the name of the promotor and an optional comment should be stored
  as version information.</s> What is left here is the stuff for statics (PatchLines).

  <li/><code>module-status</code>; shows the latest status of a module (latest
  promoted version in the VCS etc.).

  <li/>Other stuff:<br/>

       <ul>

         <li/>Windows as well as Linux is supported.

	 <li/>Documentation available : User Guide; *** including the concepts
	      / development process we perceive ***, proper Javadoc (if only
	      for ourselves), website (generated with nightly build
	      mechanism). Very important is a 'management-type'
	      presentation. Also describe soft issues !!!!

         <li/>Webstart enabled deployment of the application including all
              dependencies. The 'KISS' principle.

       </ul>

</ul>

</section>

<section name="NOT supported in version 1.0">

<ul>

  <li/>Deployment commands will not be implemented. Local implementations will
  have to cater for it (such as an ANT build script). This includes properties
  and resources. It is very important, but not in this release.

  <li/>No graphical user interface will be available.

  <li/>No plugins will be available for IDE's

  <li/>Generating release notes, not even recording the items for the release
  notes. In later versions, release notes can be generated.

  <li/>No commands for generating documentation is provided.

  <li/>Module history. Older versions etc. 'Tag'-based maybe.

</ul>

</section>

</body>

</document>
