<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Reference Documentation</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Java enterprise application modules">
      <p>
        This type of module defines one Java enterprise application. A Java enterprise
        application is basically a collection of Java web applications, EJBs, libraries,
        etc. It does not contain any sources and therefor also no unit tests.
      </p>
      <p>
        The sub-applications and libraries are defined using dependencies. The
        descriptor files and other resources are stored in this module.
      </p>
      <p>
        This type of module is typically build, tested and packaged into an <code>.ear</code>
        (Enterprise ARchive) file.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section name="Layout">
      <p>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>Source</th>
            <th>Build</th>
            <th>Package</th>
            <th>Description</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/META-INF</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/META-INF</td>
            <td>
              Contains the deployment descriptors and other resources of the
              enterprise application.
              <br/>
              A special file is the <code>application.xml</code>. This is the
              main descriptor file and is therefor mandatory.
              <p>
                <b>Note:</b> the descriptor files typically contain references
                to <code>.jar</code> files, <code>.war</code> files and web applications.
                Since these files and applications are version managed by Karma they
                automatically recieve a version number in their (file) name, which
                is dynamic. To handle this, without the need to change the descriptor files
                everytime a version changes, Karma offers keyword replacement for this.
                <br/>
                When Karma encounters a tag like <code>@module_name@</code> in the resource
                files, this tag will be replaced by <code>module_artifact</code>. E.g.
                <code>@karma-core@</code> might be replaced with <code>karma-core_1-0</code>.
              </p>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;module dependencies&gt;</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/</td>
            <td>
              Module dependencies will be packaged into the <code>.ear</code> file
              when the dependency's attribute <code>package</code> equals <code>true</code>.
              The module dependencies are placed into the root of the <code>.ear</code>
              file.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;jar dependencies&gt;</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/lib</td>
            <td>
              Jar dependencies will be packaged into the <code>.ear</code> file
              when the dependency's attribute <code>package</code> equals <code>true</code>.
              The jar dependencies are placed into the <code>/lib</code> directory
              of the <code>.ear</code> file.
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>