<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Reference Documentation</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Java source modules">
      <p>
        A Java source module contains java sources, as well as the corresponding
        unit tests and resources.
        <br/>
        This type of module is typically build, tested and packaged into a <code>.jar</code>
        file.
      </p>

    </section>
    <section name="Layout">
      <p>
      </p>
      <p>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>Source</th>
            <th>Build</th>
            <th>Package</th>
            <th>Description</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/java</td>
            <td>build</td>
            <td>/</td>
            <td>
              Contains the Java sources of the module. These sources are built to
              the build directory of a module's Karma build directory. The compiled
              <code>.class</code> files are packaged into the root of the
              <code>.jar</code> file prepended with their package.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/resources</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/</td>
            <td>
              Contains resources to be used by the Java code in this module. The contents
              of this directory are copied 1-to-1 to the root of the <code>.jar</code> file,
              so that they end up in the classpath.
              <br/>
              The resources are put on the classpath during the test step.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/META-INF</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/META-INF</td>
            <td>
              Files to be stored in the <code>META-INF</code> directory of the
              <code>.jar</code> file. These files are not used during the build or test step.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>test/java</td>
            <td>test</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>
              Contains the unit tests for the Java sources in this module. There
              is no limitation on the class name of the unit tests. All classes in
              this directory are supposed to be unit tests.
              <br/>
              During the test step the compiled tests end up in the test directory
              of the module's Karma build directory.
              <br/>
              The unit test classes are not packaged into the <code>.jar</code> file.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>test/resources</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>
              Contains resources used by the unit tests. The files in this directory
              are placed on the classpath when running the unit tests.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;module dependencies&gt;</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>
              Dependencies on source modules are used during building and testing.
              These dependencies are not packaged into the <code>.jar</code> file.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;jar dependencies&gt;</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>
              Dependencies on <code>.jar</code> files, either via a Maven-like
              dependency or via a library module dependency, are used when building
              and testing. They are not packaged into the module's <code>.jar</code> file.
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </p>
   </section> 
 </body>
</document>