<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Reference Documentation</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Java web application modules">
      <p>
        This type of module defines one Java web application. It contains all Java
        sources (for the servlets, e.g.), web content (JSPs and HTML, e.g.) and
        resources that are needed for the web application.
      </p>
      <p>
        This type of module is typically build, tested and packaged into a <code>.war</code>
        (Web ARchive) file.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section name="Layout">
      <p>
        <table>
          <tr>
            <th>Source</th>
            <th>Build</th>
            <th>Package</th>
            <th>Description</th>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/java</td>
            <td>build/WEB-INF/classes</td>
            <td>/WEB-INF/classes</td>
            <td>
              Contains all java source files needed for the web application. Typically,
              these will be Servlet classes, action classes, etc.
              <br/>
              When packaged, the built classes end up in the <code>WEB-INF/classes</code>
              directory of the <code>.war</code> file, which is on the classpath of a web
              application.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/resources</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/WEB-INF/classes</td>
            <td>
              The resources needed when testing and running the web application. These
              resources are on the classpath when running the unit tests. They end
              up in the <code>WEB-INF/classes</code> directory of the <code>.war</code>
              file, which puts them in the runtime classpath as well.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>test/java</td>
            <td>test</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>
              Contains the unit tests for the Java sources in this module. There
              is no limitation on the class name of the unit tests. All classes in
              this directory are supposed to be unit tests.
              <br/>
              During the test step the compiled tests end up in the test directory
              of the module's Karma build directory.
              <br/>
              The unit test classes are not packaged into the <code>.war</code> file.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>test/resources</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>
              Contains resources used by the unit tests. The files in this directory
              are placed on the classpath when running the unit tests.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/web</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/</td>
            <td>
              Contains the web content of the web application that needs to be
              reacheable from the outside (by clients).
              <br/>
              Typically, this content will be HTML files, images and JSP files.
              <br/>
              The content of this directory is put in the root of the <code>.war</code>
              file.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>src/web/WEB-INF</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/WEB-INF</td>
            <td>
              This directory contains all web content that is not meant to be called
              from outside the application.
              <br/>
              Typically, this content will be HTML files, images and JSP files.
              <br/>
              One special files is the <code>web.xml</code> file, which is the
              descriptor of the web application. This file needs to be present.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;module dependencies&gt;</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/WEB-INF/lib</td>
            <td>
              Module dependencies are used during building and testing. They are
              put on the classpath at that time.
              <br/>
              Module dependencies of which the attribute <code>package</code> equals
              <code>true</code>, are packaged into the <code>.war</code> file. They
              are placed in the <code>WEB-INF/lib</code> directory.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>&lt;jar dependencies&gt;</td>
            <td>-</td>
            <td>/WEB-INF/lib</td>
            <td>
              Jar dependencies are used during building and testing. They are
              put on the classpath at that time.
              <br/>
              Jar dependencies of which the attribute <code>package</code> equals
              <code>true</code>, are packaged into the <code>.war</code> file. They
              are placed in the <code>WEB-INF/lib</code> directory.
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>